Era of Warring States
W-Wait...
A-Are you sure he's an Uchiha?
Yes...
If he's found out that you're Senju,
he'll pretend to let his guard down
to steal intel on us.
Do not trust him.
No, he's not like that...
You'd trust the clan who killed
your younger brother?
You have no idea what
he's thinking inside his gut!
If he tricks you, you'll be putting
the entire Senju Clan at risk.
That's not...
Just in case, Tobirama and I
will come along. Understood?
Answer me!
Yes.
I know it's right off the bat,
but how about we just skip stones
instead of exchanging greetings?
Yeah...
Hashirama...
Sorry. I can't stay today...
I just remembered something
I have to do.
O-Oh yeah?
I'm going to head home then.
RUN
TRAP, SCRAM
That speed!
He's planning to run for it!
Damn Hashirama!
He warned him!
Let's go, Tobirama!
Yes!
Seems like we're both
on the same page.
Butsuma Senju.
And Tobirama, I believe.
Indeed, Tajima Uchiha.
And Izuna, right?
It seemed the Uchiha coincidentally
had the same idea.
Exactly the same circumstances.
Butsuma Senju and Tajima Uchiha
both knew from numerous prior clashes
that they possessed
practically equal strength.
- Stop!
Shinobi are trained to keep
their hearts in check on the battlefield,
no matter what happens.
A single flash of emotional display
can lead to vulnerability
and mean the difference
between life and death.
However...
The two adults were well aware...
that if their own child were killed
right before their eyes,
it would likely, no matter how slight,
unbalance their heart.
Meaning...
whoever could land the first strike
would determine the outcome.
TRAP, SCRAM              RUN
I'll never forgive anyone who tries
to hurt my little brother,
no matter who they are!
Same here!
Hey, Hashirama...
What is it?
Maybe it just isn't possible for us...
to reach that...
pipe dream of ours...
Madara... What are you...?
It may have been brief,
but it was fun...Hashirama.
Three against three...
Can we take them, Madara?
No...
Hashirama is stronger than me.
If we fight, we'll lose.
There's a kid stronger than you, Brother?
I see, quite impressive.
Let's retreat!
So long.
Madara!
You...really haven't given up, have you?
You've gotten to the same point I...
You are Senju.
I truly wish it wasn't so.
My brothers were killed
by the Senju.
And your brothers, by the Uchiha...
So there's no need to show
our guts to each other.
Our next meeting will likely be
on the battlefield...
Hashirama Senju.
I'm...Madara Uchiha.
Father! Look at Big Brother's eyes!
We may not have obtained
any intel on the Senju...
but it seems we gained something
valuable from this, after all.
He awakened his Sharingan...just now?
In that moment,
I felt like I understood what awakening
the Sharingan truly signified.
He decided to completely
erase his friend.
To erase me from his life.
After that, we battled.
We fought each other day after day.
And before we knew it,
we'd each become
our respective clan's leaders.
We were at the furthest place possible...
from the dream that
we wanted to fulfill.
Fire Style!
Fire Ball Jutsu!
Water Style!
Water Dragon Missile!
A blind attack...
I curse the misfortune of the ones
who do not have the Sharingan.
Flying Raijin Slice!
Izuna!
Hang in there!
I swear I'll save you!
Hashirama...
Madara... You cannot defeat me.
But I had never abandoned our dream.
Why don't we end this?
If the two strongest shinobi clans,
the Uchiha and Senju, join forces,
nations will not be able to find
other shinobi clans that
can stand against us...
The conflict will eventually
start to die down.
Come on.
No... Big Brother...
Izuna!
Do not be deceived by them...
Have you forgotten that
these bastards killed everyone...
killed the Uchiha?
It was clear to all that the Uchiha Clan
was in an unfavorable position.
In fact, defectors to the Senju
soon began showing up.
And that's about when
Madara changed as well.
He had obtained
the Eternal Mangekyo Sharingan.
Those eyes...
What happened to Izuna?
My little brother ended up dying
from that day's wounds...
Leaving me powers that
will help protect the Uchiha!
I sent you a cease-fire agreement!
If you truly want to protect the Uchiha,
let's stop fighting!
Hashirama!
Wood Style, Deep Forest Bloom!
Poison Pollen eh?
Enough, Madara!
Fighting is meaningless!
Meaningless?
Then why did Izuna die?
It's because....
because you bastards killed him!
Wood Golem Jutsu!
Hashirama!
Madara, we were friends!
And we shared the same dream!
Hashirama!
How long will you keep saying
such juvenile things?
It's just not possible to show
our guts to each other!
Don't you get it?
Hashirama!
Madara!
At the end of a battle
that lasted a whole day...
Madara's back touched
the ground for the very first time.
Madara...
You're finished.
Wait, Tobirama.
Why, Elder Brother?!
This is our chance!
No one touches him!
Just get it over with, Hashirama.
It would be an honor to die
by your hand.
Stop posturing.
If I kill the clan leader of the Uchiha,
it will only incite the young ones
who follow you.
There isn't anyone left with such pluck
among the Uchiha anymore.
Sure there are.
Perhaps not right now, but in time.
Come on...
Why don't we end this war?
We made a promise, remember?
To create the ideal village someday.
Can't we go back to those days...
and skip rocks together?
That's just impossible.
You and I are no longer the same.
Let's build our settlement here!
Heh... You're pretty much the only one
spouting such nonsense.
Well then, what about you?
Yeah... If that settlement gets built here,
then I could watch over
my little brother,
and protect him in this place
where you can see to no end!
I don't have a single brother left.
I have nothing to protect.
And...I just can't trust you.
Is there any way I can
convince you to trust us?
Well, there is a way to
show each other our guts...
Either kill your brother...
or kill yourself right now.
And then we'll be even.
I'd be willing to trust your clan.
Kill your little brother or kill yourself?
How dare you say
something so ridicu-
I agree.
This is crazy!
So what are you going
to do, Elder Brother?
Are you going to kill me now?
Or are you going to die on account
of this guy's nonsense?
It's idiotic. Don't listen to him!
Thank you, Madara.
You really are kindhearted.
Madara had given me a choice,
an option where I wouldn't have
to kill my little brother.
He knew all too well...
how an older brother feels
towards his younger siblings.
Listen, Tobirama...
Etch these words into your heart,
for these are my final words...
Brother...
Words that I shall be exchanging
with my life.
You too, my fellow clan members.
After my death, do not kill Madara.
I forbid any fighting between
the Uchiha and Senju.
Swear this right now...
upon the lives of your fathers,
and your grandchildren yet unborn.
Farewell...
Enough...
I have now seen your guts.
It was like a dream...
The Uchiha and the Senju
formed an alliance.
There would no longer
be any casualties,
nor would any more children
have to die.
And so, we began building our village.
Do you remember how we used
to talk here when we were brats?
Yeah... I thought we were just talking
about our dream.
That dream is now becoming a reality.
There's no time to be weak right now!
We're going to need to come up
with a name for the village too!
Any thoughts?
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"My True Dream"
How about
the Village Hidden in the Leaves?
MY TRUE DREAM
Tune in again!